<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://krajeshkumar14.github.io/Art/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://krajeshkumar14.github.io/Art/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-12T05:50:07-05:00</updated><id>https://krajeshkumar14.github.io/Art/feed.xml</id><title type="html">கலை</title><subtitle>A blog for Art</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Imagemaking</title><link href="https://krajeshkumar14.github.io/Art/imagemaking%20graphic-design/2020/07/12/imagemaking.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Imagemaking" /><published>2020-07-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://krajeshkumar14.github.io/Art/imagemaking%20graphic-design/2020/07/12/imagemaking</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://krajeshkumar14.github.io/Art/imagemaking%20graphic-design/2020/07/12/imagemaking.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name implies, &lt;strong&gt;Imagemaking&lt;/strong&gt; is the process of producing images from real life entities, either literally or metaphorically. The literal depiction of an object results in &lt;a href=&quot;#denotative-images&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Denotative Images&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the metaphorical depiction results in &lt;a href=&quot;#connotative-images&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connotative Images&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Art/images/apple.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Denotative image(left) and Connotative image(right)&quot; /&gt;
For example, in the above image, there are two depictions of the fruit &lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt;. The one on the left is a generic depiction of an Apple, by itself. The depiction is straightforward and hence a &lt;strong&gt;denotative&lt;/strong&gt; image. The one on the right has the apple slightly rotated and has a few streaks of lines above it. These two simple modifications now give another perspective to the image: now it depicts &lt;strong&gt;gravity&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;gravitational force&lt;/strong&gt;. Thus, the modifications has made it a &lt;strong&gt;connotative&lt;/strong&gt; image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;denotative-imagemaking&quot;&gt;Denotative Imagemaking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Denotative image is an exact representation of the object.&lt;/em&gt; The first meaning it implies will be that of the object itself. When you see a picture of a cube against a white canvas, first thing that comes to mind is ‘It’s a cube’. There is no confusion whether it is a sphere or a cube, the meaning is straightforward, &lt;em&gt;it’s a cube&lt;/em&gt;. It will be hard for a viewer to look at a denotative image and get any other message from the image other than the fact that the image is of the object being portrayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An object, in the context of denotative imagemaking, has multiple states. For example, an apple, can be portrayed as ripe, unripe, half-eaten, eaten-to-core, rotten, cut, etc. The method of portraying the image can also be various: the representation can be a &lt;em&gt;simple&lt;/em&gt; line drawing, or a &lt;em&gt;complex&lt;/em&gt; illustration, but either way the object being portrayed is clear. This is called the detail of the image. The more detail it is, the more  &lt;strong&gt;photorealistic&lt;/strong&gt; it is said to be, and the lesser the detail, more simple. Thus, it is upto the creator of the image to convey it in whatever level of detail he entices, as long as the image is able to be interpreted in literal meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;imagemaking-techniques&quot;&gt;Imagemaking Techniques&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Introduction</summary></entry></feed>